She and
Her Cat
She and Her Cat
Yeah, Daru's doing fine, too.
Even for such an old boy.
I'm thinking of working hard as
a part-timer for another year.
My mom? No, we haven't talked at all.
What? She called you? My mom?
Sorry.
She probably said some weird stuff, huh?
The shadows are getting longer.
This is the season my fur
coat comes in handy.
I sleep longer now, and more
deeply, than I used to.
Sec. 3 【She and the Look in Her Eyes】
I don't remember where I was,
or what I did, before I became her cat.
But I do remember my mother.
She was kind, warm,
and gave me everything I wanted.
When I was small and weak,
she kept me here in this world.
But my mother and siblings all disappeared.
I don't remember what happened.
We don't have the ability
to remember everything.
We only remember the truly important things.
Faraway things look small and hazy,
and nearby things appear clearly.
Memories are the same.
The old ones are hazy,
but I clearly remember things
that have just happened.
Or so I thought...
But lately, for some reason,
I remember things from long ago
as if they were very recent.
Oh, right, sorry.
My body doesn't move very well.
I've lived quite a long life already.
I wonder how old my mother was...
If my mother were alive, is there
anything she'd want to tell me?
Like her mother does...
I'm moving out.
I'll live on my own.
You will not.
Why?
There are schools you can
commute to from here.
And living alone costs money.
Why don't you start living with a husband?
The timing's right.
Stay here until you get a job.
I don't intend to remarry until then.
You should find your happiness.
Your happiness is my happiness!
Saying you do everything for me
is just forcing excuses on me!
Well, you...
You don't even want me to remarry, do you?
That's not true!
Why is it always like this?
She'll never be happy if
she doesn't let me go.
But
I always want to be with her, too...
And Daru...
She comes home later now.
It feels like that only happened recently,
but also like it was a long time ago.
In the warm darkness,
surrounded by her smell,
I just wait for her to come home.
I'm home.
She always comes home exhausted.
She brings the smell of a
faraway town I don't know.
Come to think of it, this place
smelled unfamiliar at first, too.
Okay, I'm going.
Do you have to take Daru-chan, too?
Well, he's my cat.
Come home anytime, okay?
I'm not coming home.
You should hurry up and get married.
Only the things you say are so mature...
Try not to cause trouble for Tomoka-chan.
Yeah.
Remember to lock the door.
It'll just be you two girls, you know.
I know.
Take care of her, okay, Daru-chan?
Daru-chan!
Let's be friends!
I guess it starts now, huh?
That's right! Our new life starts now!
This is your mother. Are you well?
Come home sometimes, would you?
You live so close.
We were talking again today
about how worried we are...
So you can't make it to the wedding?
Too bad...
Hey, we'll have the after-party
on a different day,
so let me know when you're free!
Tomoka...
I'm sorry. I can't handle it right now.
Why can't I move forward?
I wish I were stronger, more of an adult...
Help me...
Her sadness and pain gripped my heart.
I know that she tries harder than anyone.
I want to help her...
But I can't even reach her anymore.