She and
Her Cat
She and Her Cat
Somewhere far away and unknown,
I was searching for her.
I'm searching for her because
she is searching for me.
Her smell...
On the other side of that heavy iron door...
Thanks for staying with me for so long.
No, no!
I should apologize for moving out first,
after I invited you to live here with me...
It's okay. Sharing this
place helped me out a lot.
A year and a half, huh?
It flew by so fast.
Hey, Daru!
You're awake?
What? Did you come to say goodbye to me?
Daru...
Aww...
He never really got to like me.
Oh, I have to go.
Tell your boyfriend I said hi.
Sure.
Good luck.
You, too, Tomoka.
And you'd better live a long life!
You're an old man already.
Bye.
I love her.
I am her cat.
Sec. 1 【She and Her Apartment】
On the hottest day of the summer...
She's gone...
We'll have to look for a new place.
The friend she was living with moved out,
and life with just the two of us began.
Every morning, she wakes at the
same time and prepares my breakfast.
The same meal as always,
the same kind girl as always.
With her fur always perfectly in
place, she's prettier than anyone
as she stands up straight and
walks out into the morning light.
I'll be back soon.
Hello? This is your mother.
3.8
Milk
I know.
What other choice do I have?
It's expensive everywhere.
I won't come home.
You said you were going
to share an apartment.
Now you're just going to start living alone?
This wasn't the deal we agreed on.
You'll be graduating soon...
Sorry. My bath's ready.
I applied to this company because
I've loved books since I was little,
and I'm especially interested
in making picture books.
I've loved animals since I was little...
I've loved homes since I was little,
and I always wanted to work in real estate...
Yeah, that won't work.
After careful consideration,
we have decided to postpone your acceptance.
We will hold on to your
résumé for the time being.
Tomoka
Oh,
your top choice fell through?
But you still have lots of time!!
Do your best!!
Tomoka
Oh,
your top choice fell through?
But you still have lots of time!!
Do your Best!!
I am doing my best.
I don't understand anything anymore...
The pain she feels carries over to me.
There's nothing I can do to ease her pain.
The next day...
Just like every other day,
she was beautiful and kind...
Morning, Daru.
...as she gave me that smile I love.
Yet again, she stands up straight
and opens the heavy door.
On the other side of the door
is an imperfect world that's also a bit cruel.
She's doing her best to
learn to love that world.
And for that, I love her very much.
The wind polishes the sky,
as if preparing to greet the next morning
Our two hearts intertwined,
guide us to where it leads
As our eyes meet,
again and again,
Let us embrace the warmth burning in our hearts,
and open that door