The daylight hours grew shorter,
and the world was enveloped
in freezing cold.
Badly hurting, she just continued
to sleep, like a large cat.
Sec. 4 【She and Her Story】
Yes, hello?
Miyu? What have you been doing?
I've been worried.
Hello? Miyu?
What's wrong? Are you all right?
Miyu?! Miyu!
Miyu...
P-Police...
You're...
Mom?
Miyu...
Huh?
So I was certain something
had happened to you.
Like what?
Well, something.
You wouldn't even answer your cell phone.
That was...
Good boy.
You're pretty old now, you know.
You need to keep the place clean,
since Daru-chan's here.
I don't want someone who hates
cleaning to tell me that.
Your husband must have it rough.
Call him "Dad," would you?
Kinda late for that, isn't it?
He might just be moved to tears.
Still, I wonder what that call was.
It was probably Daru.
You're blaming Daru-chan again?
Maybe he jumped up there
and pushed the buttons?
And happened to call me? Imagine that.
I see! So you missed me, huh, Daru-chan?
Oh?
Guess not.
The same laughter I heard back then...
Thanks for worrying about me.
Oh, don't mention it.
Well, I feel much better, so I'll go now.
They're both all right now.
I'll visit home sometime, too.
Daru? Did you fall asleep?
Daru?
Surrounded by her scent,
I fell into my longest sleep yet.
A deep, long, peaceful, happy sleep.
I've always has a strong
admiration for this sound.
It's a very regular, powerful sound...
The sound of the world's heart sending
power to its every last corner.
In the room where she and I lived,
though my time and hers no
longer exist together...
The world still moves,
and we still travel upon it.
Daru...
So one day, I know we'll once again...
So then I got an earful for always
closing the door so slowly,
and I remembered it was a habit
I picked up because of Daru.
He always did love getting
into tight places.
Yeah. Stuff like that makes
me feel a little down, but...
I'm so glad you're feeling better, though.
I was really worried about you.
Thanks.
If I keep moping around,
it'll make Daru worry, right?
Yeah, it's been a whole year, hasn't it?
Oh, right! We have to
celebrate your new job!
We kept putting it off!
Sure. Thanks, Tomoka.
It was the beginning of spring,
on a rainy day.
Beneath a soft curtain of rain,
I was thinking of a long journey I
would never be able to remember.
At the end of a long, long journey,
I ended up here.
I forgot a lot of things,
but there's one thing I faintly remember.
Her scent.
Earth turned quietly on its axis,
and in the midst of this big world,
she and I quietly lost body heat together.
Just as our heat and our breaths
flow across this planet,
she and I flowed across the planet,
and ended up here so we
could meet once again.
Come on, let's go.
That was the day she took me home.
And that's why I'm her cat.
She and Her Cat